# 大家好 今天來兄弟家的這個山彩山雞場啊
Hi everyone! Today we come to our buddy's pheasant farm,
# 來看一下
and have a look around.
# 兄弟都走了 不知道他跑哪裡去了
My buddy has already left. God knows where he is.
# 剛剛還打電話還說在在在在 現在就跑了
He just said, "yea, yea, yea, yea, I'm here" on the phone. But now he has run away.
# 我進去看一下
Let me have a look inside.
# 防疫區域 閑人免進
Epidemic control area. No unauthorised entry.
# 跟他說了 他說叫我們可以進
I've talked with him. He said that we can get in.
# 這消一下毒 這有消毒嗎
We need to be sanitised. Here's the sanitiser.
# 叫兄弟抓一隻山雞來 兄弟不在
I asked my buddy to catch me a pheasant. But he's not around.
# 叫他們的工人來抓
So I asked his workers to catch me one.
# 好多啊 這裡
Really a lot, here.
# 這些山雞全部都戴了眼鏡
These pheasant are all wearing eye shields,
# 這它們不要打架
to prevent them from fighting.
# 它現在就看不到前面
Now they can't see the front.
# 看不 看不到前面就不會那個
When they can't, can't see the front, they won't, you know,
# 不會你啄我我啄你
they won't perk each other all the time.
# 那裡有一條門 這邊也有一條門
There's a door. And here's another door.
# 你看 這個
Look! These,
# 這個雞都戴了那個眼鏡的哦 都是後面戴上去的
these pheasants are all wearing that kind of eye shields. They were put on from the back.
# 這個快掉了
This one is falling off.
# 還想啄我
You wanna perk me?
# 它應該看不到 它應該看不到前面
They shouldn't be able, shouldn't be able to see the front.
# 那麼乖
Good pheasants!
# 這個會飛的哦這個 一跑出去就抓不到了都
They can fly, you know. It's impossible to catch them once they're outside.
# 踩著它
It's stepping on it.
# 你看
Look!
# 應該可以進去哦 我們進去看一下
I think I can get in. Let's have a look inside.
# 你看 這一棟 這幾個棚裡面應該有幾千隻
Look! I think there are thousands of pheasants in this lodge, in this couple of sheds
# 那麼多 他這裡有幾棟哦
So many. He has dozens of lodges here.
# 究竟多少棟我也不知道 最少 最少有三四十棟 這樣的
I've no ideas how many exactly. But I think there are at least, at least thirty or forty lodges, sort of.
# 加起來應該有
Together, there should be,
# 五六萬七八萬都有 七八萬隻啦
fifty, sixty or seventy, or even eighty thousand pheasants, yea, up to eighty thousand.
# 這一個規模
This scale is,
# 夠大
huge.
# 那麼乖的 那麼聽話
What a good, nice and gentle pheasant.
# 去不去 帶你去
Are you coming with me? I'll take you to,
# 帶你去那個
take you to, you know,
# 帶你去 帶你去玩
take you to, take you to have some fun.
# 有一點濕 剛才下過雨
It's a bit wet. It has just rained.
# 你看 那屋頂上都站了有
Look! Some are standing on the roof beam there.
# 它們那麼調皮
They're so naughty.
# 抓都抓不到它們
It's simply impossible to catch them.
# 好啦 回去啦回去啦
Alright! Let's go, let's go.
# 你看 這邊也有 那邊也有
Look! Here are some lodges, and there too,
# 那後面也有 這邊也有一大片哦
and at our back too, and this side too, the whole area.
# 將近上萬隻哦 這裡
Here are almost ten thousand pheasants, here.
# 那麼多
So many
# 你看 這些都是母的哦 小母雞 那個漂亮一點的就是公的
Look! There are all female, you know, little hens. Those prettier ones are male.
# 兄弟還搞了另外一個場所哦 比這裡大幾倍哦
My buddy has started another site, which is a few times larger than this one.
# 上那邊 上次我去看過 但是還沒建成
It's over there. I went there last time, but it was still under construction.
# 現在也開始在動工啦
Now the construction work has already commenced.
# 這個七彩山雞 那個肉質很好吃的哦
The pheasant, their meat, the texture of their meat, is really tasty.
# 上次兄弟送了幾個給我吃了一下
My buddy gave me a couple of them last time.
# 嘖 搞的我回味無窮 今天又來啦
It's a taste that I can never forget. That's why I'm here again today.
# 我們再搞一個來
Let's get one more.
# 兄弟也太客氣啦
My buddy is just too nice to me.
# 就給了那麼一點給我
He gave me this little bit here.
# 哎呀
Aya!
# 可以
Fine!
# 你看
Look!
# 殺好啦
It's now ready.
# 好有肉哇 雞肉
It's really meaty, pheasant meat.
# 把內臟取一下 然後再放點油鹽腌一下
Let me take out the guts. And then marinate it with some oil and salt.
# 你看 這個公的哦
Look! This is male.
# 還有蛋的看到沒有 留起來等一下一人一個
It has balls, see? Leave them here and we can have one each.
# 我要刮一下它的這個
I need to scratch it, I mean,
# 割它幾刀
slice it a few times.
# 更入味
It will be more flavourful.
# 你看 這個 這個雞
Look! This, this pheasant,
# 身上都沒有肥肉的哦
has hardly any fat on its body.
# 有一點點 你看 幾乎都沒有
Perhaps a bit. Look! But almost none.
# 這個塞回去
I stuff it back inside.
# 把它腳
Its feet...
# 拗過來
Twist them
# 先腌一下它 所以把它
Marinate it first. So I have to,
# 裹起來
wrap it up.
# 然後就 這樣把它裹起一團
And then, wrap it up into a ball,
# 再來燒
then cook it.
# 絕對美味
Good taste is guaranteed.
# 好啦 拿一個盤子來把它腌一下
Alright! I take a pot here and marinate it for a while.
# 切的慢
I chop too slowly.
# 生薑加大蒜
Ginger with garlic,
# 放到你身上
onto your body
# 嗯 再加點料酒
Um! Then put some cooking wine.
# 還有一點點
There's still a tiny little bit.
# 夠啦 夠啦
Enough, enough
# 下次去兄弟家搞幾瓶過來
I'll get a few bottles from my buddy next time.
# 現在攝影小哥越來越吃辣椒啦
Now Mr. Cameraman can have more and more chilli.
# 口味越來越重
He's becoming a fanatic of intense flavour.
# 放點辣椒下去
Put some chilli.
# 醬油
Soy sauce
# 加點油下去 如果不加油的話
Let me put some oil. Without oil,
# 到時候會燒焦的
it would get burnt.
# 鹽呢
Where's the salt?
# 加點
Put some,
# 加點鹽
put some salt.
# 差不多夠啦
It should be enough.
# 就是那麼小的雞
It's only a small pheasant.
# 給它搓一搓
Let me rub it over the body.
# 讓這個
Let it,
# 讓這個薑汁
let the ginger juice,
# 在他身上
to be sprayed evenly,
# 塗抹均勻
on its body.
# 按一下摩
Give it a massage
# 這樣肉質很好吃的哦
Then the texture would be really wonderful.
# 養了已經超過8個月啦
My buddy has been raising this pheasant for more than eight months.
# 等一下我們做個叫花雞
Let's make a Beggar's Pheasant in a while.
# 去搞點荷葉回來
Let's go and fetch some lotus leaves.
# 等下我去 叫兄弟家拿幾個香菇過來
I'm gonna, gonna ask my buddy to bring me some shiitake mushrooms from his place.
# 我家的香菇
My mushrooms,
# 不在這裡
are not here.
# 裹起來 用荷葉把它裹起來
Wrap it up, wrap it up with lotus leaves,
# 然後再來烤
and then we can grill it.
# 味道一定很鮮美
It must be very flavourful and savoury.
# 好啦 把它放回 放到桌子上去
Alright! Let me put it back, onto the table.
# 等下被這個小狗給吃啦
I can't let the doggies take it.
# 那虧大啦
It would be too bad.
# 你看 這是我兄弟家哦
Look! This is my buddy's home.
# 那有狗 有條狗守在那裡
There's a dog. A dog is guarding the place.
# 他家的荷葉就是這裡
His lotus leaves are right here.
# 哎喲 好兇哦
Aya! So fierce
# 你看 這狗擋住道路啦
Look! The dog is blocking the way.
# 好兇的
So fierce
# 好狗 好狗
Good dog, good dog!
# 到那邊去拗 不著急喲
I'm picking on that side. No hurry,
# 這邊也有啊
Here are also some lotus leaves.
# 好啦 夠啦 不要摘那麼多
Alright! Enough! Not too many
# 我摯穹點那個黃泥回來 就在那裡
I'm gonna dig some mud. It's right over there,
# 很近的
not far at all.
# 挖一點黃泥
Dig some mud.
# 一鋤頭
Put down the hoe,
# 可以挖好多
and a lot of mud comes down.
# 好啦 可以啦
Alright! It's enough.
# 一下子搞一大盆
A whole pot of mud is here in seconds.
# 哎喲 哎喲 好重
Ayo, ayo! So heavy!
# 這個黃泥
The mud,
# 很新
is so fresh,
# 你看 這個黃泥很新鮮哦
Look! The mud is really fresh, isn't it?
# 這個黃泥加點水
Put some water, into the mud.
# 要把它攪拌 攪拌均勻
I need to mix it, mix it well.
# 然後要把它
And then I'll need to,
# 搞成
make it,
# 搞成那個 黏笘的那一種啊
make it into, something like, sticky.
# 等下就
I'm gonna,
# 把你給煮啦
have you cooked very soon.
# 這裡還有五六隻雞喲
Here are still half a dozen of pheasants.
# 放在這裡
I leave them here,
# 慢慢烤
and grill them all,
# 一天烤一個
gradually, one per day.
# 好啦
Alright!
# 可以啦 等下把這黃泥塗上去就好啦
Alright! Then I only need to paste the mud in a while.
# 先洗個手
Let me wash my hands first,
# 把那雞裹好來
and then wrap up the pheasant.
# 把它放到這裡來
Put it here.
# 把這個香菇
Stuff the shiitake mushrooms,
# 塞到它
into its,
# 肚子裡面
its belly.
# 然後 這個醬汁
And then, here's the sauce
# 不要浪費
Don't waste it.
# 倒進去
Pour it inside.
# 裹著它
Wrap it up.
# 這樣就
Then it's,
# 就靚哦 在[SIC]裹一層
really beautiful. One more layer
# 要把它壓緊一點
I need to press it tight.
# 要結實一點
It needs to be firm.
# 這樣它才跑不了
Only then can it never run away.
# 嗯 好啦
Um! Alright!
# 我們裹點黃泥上去
Let's wrap it with some mud.
# 去 看一下 (註︰沒有原字幕)
Alright! Let's go and see what's next.
# 你看 外面下雨 沒苏法啦 只能在家裡烤
Look! It's raining outside and we have no choice but grilling it at home.
# 我要先把它那個
I'm gonna put the,
# 雞放到這上面去
pheasant here on top first.
# 這底下要鋪層泥喲
There needs to be a layer of mud at the bottom.
# 鋪層泥等下一燒的話就剛剛好
A layer of mud will make it just perfect once we start grilling.
# 好啦
Alright!
# 把這個雞放到這裡來
Let me put the pheasant here.
# 慢慢的把這個泥粘上去
Then I paste the mud onto it bit by bit.
# 這樣就不用
Then I don't need to,
# 不用動啦
I don't need to move it.
# 要不要給你玩 胡韦汝來
You wanna play with it? Come, Hu Weiru!
# 做那個 你看
I can make a, look,
# 做這個糍粑哦 你看
make this mud cake, look!
# 那麼好玩 你不玩
It's so much fun! Why don't you want it?
# 還小的時候我們玩具都沒有 就玩這個
We didn't even have a single piece of toy when we were kids. And this was our toy.
# 那個袋子掉下去啦
That bag fell onto the ground.
# 沒事
No worries
# 是它看到 看到我們把它的同 同伴
It's because, it sees that we're, turning its companion,
# 變成了一個蛋
into an egg,
# 所以它就怕
That's why it's scared.
# 好啦 明天來 明天就輪到它啦
Alright! Tomorrow, tomorrow will be its turn.
# 你看
Look!
# 把它搞成一個蛋一樣
I've turned it into something like an egg.
# 開始點火
Let's start the fire.
# 它們的炭都燒著啦
Their charcoal has been lighted.
# 這下雨天
In a rainy day,
# 太難 這個火太難點啦
it's super hard, super hard to set a fire.
# 直接抱了把稻草下來
So I've taken some straw down here right away.
# 現在多加點炭下去
Now I put a bit more charcoal.
# 現在又下雨啦
It rains again now.
# 天天下雨 搞很河邊去都去不了
It rains every day. There's no way to go to the riverside.
# 逼在家裡
We can only stay at home.
# 在河邊的話我們大火來燒它
We could grill it with a strong fire if we could go to the riverside.
# 這也
Anyway,
# 也沒辦法
we have no choice.
# 你看 這個天又出太陽啦
Look! The sun is shinning in the sky once again.
# 剛剛還下大雨 你看 等下那片烏雲又飛過來啦
It was still raining heavily a few moments ago. Look! That dark cloud will be coming here in a while.
# 又啪啦一降 降 降一個大水下來
Then "pala"! The, the rain pours again.
# 啊 看一下 這個好啦
Ah! Let's have a look. It's alright now.
# 你看 這個 差不多快好了哦
Look! This is, almost done, I suppose.
# 那麼多
So much,
# 四 四面八方都是炭 圍著它
the charcoal from every, every direction, is surrounding it.
# 在[SIC]煮一個小時
One more hour
# 全是狗
All are dogs
# 就小黑有名字 其它都沒名字
Only Blacky has a name. All others are nameless.
# 你看 現在都紅啦
Look! It's red now, wa!
# 應該熟啦
It should be done now.
# 拿這個鋤頭來
I take this hoe.
# 哇 你看 終於搞起來啦
Wa! Look! We pick it up finally.
# 上上面去
Let's go up there,
# 上面去看一下熟了沒有
go up there and see if it's done.
# 還熟啦
It's done!
# 哎呦 下大雨啦
Ayo! The rain pours again.
# 哎呀 別 別 別那個
Aya! Don't, don't, don't, I mean,
# 別沖走就麻煩啦
don't wash it away. It would be too bad.
# 你看 這荷葉都燒焦啦
Look! Even the lotus leaves are burnt.
# 哎呀
Aya!
# 看上去就好吃
The appearance is already confirming the taste.
# 輕輕的撕開
Tear it open lightly.
# 撕開裡面
Tear the inside open.
# 好香啊
It smells so good!
# 哎喲
Ayo!
# 有刀
Here's a knife.
# 嗯 熟啦
Um! It's done!
# 熟啦 熟啦 熟啦 全部熟啦
Done, done, done, well done.
# 嗯
Um!
# 可以喲
It's not bad!
# 嘿 等一下來
Hey! A moment!
# 等一下來 等我吃完再說
A moment! Let me finish first.
# 剛才不是還有塊骨頭嗎
Didn't you get a piece of bone just now?
# 全部狗都來啦
All dogs are coming here.
# 它們在排隊 等一下哦
They're queuing up. A moment, okay?
# 這還那麼多肉
There's still plenty of meat.
# 這還有一個雞腿
Here's still a leg.
# 等一下留給攝影小哥吃
I'll leave for Mr. Cameraman in a while.
# 攝影小哥不喜歡吃這樣的
Mr. Cameraman doesn't like this kind of stuff.
# 他喜歡吃那個
He likes the...
# 他喜歡吃這兩個蛋
He likes these two balls.
# 哪裡去啦
Where are they?
# 在這裡
Here
# 可以喲
It's not bad.
# 一點怪怪的味道
It tastes a bit funny.
# 額 小狗慢慢吃
Eh! Doggy! No rush!
# 還有一個
One more
# 雞腿不好吃 這個才好吃
It tastes much better than the leg, which doesn't taste good at all.
# 哎 算啦 留給攝影小哥補一補
Ay! Forget. I leave it for Mr. Cameraman to power him up.
# 沒吃過癮它們
They're still craving.
# 留一個雞眼給攝影小哥就行啦
Leaving a leg to Mr. Cameraman is everything that's needed.
# 給你吃
It's yours.
# 好啦
Alright!
# 今天的視頻
The video,
# 就到
ends,
# 這裡啦
here.